# **Hector Bustamante Ruiz**

Java Developer

(+51) 987 922 743 Lima, Perú (GMT-5) <u>hbustamanter0501@gmail.com</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/hectorbr/

Software Developer with +4 years of experience developing web applications using **Java** and **Spring** framework in microservices with a focus on process improvement and automation. Experience working with Agile methods (SCRUM). I consider myself a technology and learning enthusiast with the desire to keep learning and interested in remote Java positions.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Ontop, Java Developer & Chapter Lead — February, 2022 - Present

SaaS Company that offers hiring & payroll solutions for business. The company can help in the streamline remote hiring, compliance, and international payroll services in minutes.

- Reviewed code for the backend and responsible of the team in the absence of our tech lead as the chapter lead of compliance team.
- Responsible of Stripe integration that helped our clients to have a double verification and a more secure payment process in payroll.
- Created API microservices using Java w/ Spring to improve our payment and compliance processes that reduced the related support cases by more than 50%.
- Implemented unit and integration tests in microservices to avoid redundant bugs.

Tech Stack: Java 8-11, Spring, Postgres SQL, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, Jenkins, Grafana, Kibana, Github

## Novatronic, Java Developer — August, 2021 - February, 2022

Leading IT Company that specializes in technological solutions and services of the highest quality. It provides BPO services and solutions for digital payments and security in the banking, telecommunications, commerce, and government sectors.

- Created API RESTful using Java w/ Spring to improve interbank transaction times by 15%.
- QA Testing on functionalities to improve client experience.
- Improved and implemented good development practices using ISO Standards.

Tech Stack: Java 8-11, Spring, MySQL, Postgres SQL, Junit, Postman, SOAPUI, XML, JIRA, JBOSS, Bitbucket, SCRUM

## Superintendencia de Bancas, Seguros y AFP, Backend Developer — August, 2020 - August, 2021

Organization in charge of the regulation and supervision of the financial, insurance and private pension systems (PPS), with the aim of preserving the interest of depositors, policyholders and members of the PPS.

- Developed Java Services to automate the financial situation process of a cooperative which helped improve research analysis time by 30%.
- QA w/ JUnit, Postman to automate tests.

Tech Stack: Java, Spring, MySQL, Junit, Postman, Github, Python

## Cloud Information Solutions, Fullstack Developer—August, 2018 - August, 2020

IT Company oriented to provide solutions in the cloud and to be the virtual area of its clients, helping them to be more proactive and to generate value for their business.

- Created API RESTful using Java/Spring and NodeJS to create a management web application based on dashboards and functionalities that helped the management team to make decisions.
- Coordinated and delegated with the programming team (2-3 people) the tasks to be done for the spring.

Tech Stack: Java, Spring, MySQL, Javascript, NodeJS, Oracle JET, Github, Oracle BD, SCRUM

# **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Intermediate: Java, Javascript, NodeJS, ExpressJS, KoaJS.

Frameworks and Tools: Intermediate: Spring, Hibernate/JPA, MySQL, PostgresSQL, MongoDB, Bootstrap, JBoss, JIRA,

Bitbucket, Github.

Languages: English, Fluent (C1 Band) - Spanish, Native.

# **EDUCATION**

**Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú** – Lima, Perú Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering, August 2021